{
  "title": "韓国語単語③",
  "data": [
    { "question": "방금", "answer": ["さっき"] },
    { "question": "방향", "answer": ["方向"] },
    { "question": "번호", "answer": ["番号"] },
    { "question": "보통", "answer": ["普段"] },
    { "question": "사실", "answer": ["事実"] },
    { "question": "사전", "answer": ["辞書"] },
    { "question": "색", "answer": ["色"] },
    { "question": "서로", "answer": ["お互い"] },
    { "question": "손님", "answer": ["お客さん"] },
    { "question": "숟가락", "answer": ["スプーン"] },
    { "question": "아까", "answer": ["先ほど"] },
    { "question": "약", "answer": ["薬"] },
    { "question": "어린이", "answer": ["子供"] },
    { "question": "여성", "answer": ["女性"] },
    { "question": "옛날", "answer": ["昔"] },
    { "question": "외국인", "answer": ["外国人"] },
    { "question": "요즘", "answer": ["最近"] },
    { "question": "이상", "answer": ["以上"] },
    { "question": "이전", "answer": ["以前"] },
    { "question": "입구", "answer": ["入り口"] },
    { "question": "잠깐", "answer": ["少しの間"] },
    { "question": "점심", "answer": ["昼食"] },
    { "question": "조건", "answer": ["条件"] },
    { "question": "중학교", "answer": ["中学校"] },
    { "question": "지도", "answer": ["地図"] },
    { "question": "직업", "answer": ["職業"] },
    { "question": "창문", "answer": ["窓"] },
    { "question": "층", "answer": ["〜階"] },
    { "question": "표", "answer": ["切符"] },
    { "question": "학년", "answer": ["学年"] },
    { "question": "방법", "answer": ["方法"] },
    { "question": "배", "answer": ["船"] },
    { "question": "별", "answer": ["星"] },
    { "question": "부엌", "answer": ["台所"] },
    { "question": "사장", "answer": ["社長"] },
    { "question": "사회", "answer": ["社会"] },
    { "question": "생선", "answer": ["魚"] },
    { "question": "소설", "answer": ["小説"] },
    { "question": "손수건", "answer": ["ハンカチ"] },
    { "question": "쌀", "answer": ["お米"] },
    { "question": "야채", "answer": ["野菜"] },
    { "question": "어른", "answer": ["大人"] },
    { "question": "여기저기", "answer": ["あちこち"] },
    { "question": "역사", "answer": ["歴史"] },
    { "question": "오른쪽", "answer": ["右"] },
    { "question": "왼쪽", "answer": ["左"] },
    { "question": "이것저것", "answer": ["あれこれ"] },
    { "question": "이유", "answer": ["理由"] },
    { "question": "이제", "answer": ["今・もう"] },
    { "question": "자전거", "answer": ["自転車"] },
    { "question": "전화", "answer": ["電話"] },
    { "question": "접시", "answer": ["お皿"] },
    { "question": "주소", "answer": ["住所"] },
    { "question": "지갑", "answer": ["財布"] },
    { "question": "지하철", "answer": ["地下鉄"] },
    { "question": "차이", "answer": ["違い"] },
    { "question": "출신", "answer": ["出身"] },
    { "question": "칼", "answer": ["ナイフ"] },
    { "question": "하루", "answer": ["１日"] },
    { "question": "한자", "answer": ["漢字"] },
    { "question": "해외", "answer": ["海外"] },
    { "question": "혼자", "answer": ["1人で"] },
    { "question": "휴가", "answer": ["休暇"] },
    { "question": "경찰", "answer": ["警察"] },
    { "question": "국민", "answer": ["国民"] },
    { "question": "다리", "answer": ["橋"] },
    { "question": "사건", "answer": ["事件"] },
    { "question": "세상", "answer": ["世間"] },
    { "question": "예술", "answer": ["芸術"] },
    { "question": "자연", "answer": ["自然"] },
    { "question": "환경", "answer": ["環境"] },
    { "question": "형제", "answer": ["兄弟"] },
    { "question": "회사원", "answer": ["会社員"] },
    { "question": "힘", "answer": ["力"] },
    { "question": "관심", "answer": ["関心"] },
    { "question": "느낌", "answer": ["感じ"] },
    { "question": "부부", "answer": ["夫婦"] },
    { "question": "성격", "answer": ["性格"] },
    { "question": "시대", "answer": ["時代"] },
    { "question": "인간", "answer": ["人間"] },
    { "question": "최근", "answer": ["最近"] },
    { "question": "환자", "answer": ["患者"] },
    { "question": "슬프다", "answer": ["悲しい"] },
    { "question": "어둡다", "answer": ["暗い"] },
    { "question": "예쁘다", "answer": ["きれい"] },
    { "question": "젊다", "answer": ["若い"] },
    { "question": "짜다", "answer": ["塩辛い"] },
    { "question": "흐리다", "answer": ["濁る / 曇る"] },
    { "question": "궁금하다", "answer": ["気になる"] },
    { "question": "부드럽다", "answer": ["柔らかい"] },
    { "question": "심하다", "answer": ["ひどい"] },
    { "question": "약하다", "answer": ["弱い"] },
    { "question": "어리다", "answer": ["幼い"] },
    { "question": "이상하다", "answer": ["変"] },
    { "question": "좁은", "answer": ["狭い"] },
    { "question": "편하다", "answer": ["楽 / 気楽"] },
    { "question": "힘들다", "answer": ["大変"] },
    { "question": "무섭다", "answer": ["恐ろしい"] },
    { "question": "심각하다", "answer": ["深刻"] },
    { "question": "훌륭하다", "answer": ["立派"] },
    { "question": "아직", "answer": ["まだ"] },
    { "question": "역시", "answer": ["やっぱり"] },
    { "question": "일찍", "answer": ["早く"] },
    { "question": "전혀", "answer": ["まったく"] },
    { "question": "함께", "answer": ["一緒に"] },
    { "question": "별로", "answer": ["別に"] },
    { "question": "제대로", "answer": ["きちんと"] },
    { "question": "얼마나", "answer": ["どのくらい"] },
    { "question": "우선", "answer": ["まず"] },
    { "question": "자주", "answer": ["しょっちゅう"] },
    { "question": "절대로", "answer": ["絶対に"] },
    { "question": "혹시", "answer": ["もしかして"] },
    { "question": "점점", "answer": ["だんだん"] },
    { "question": "특히", "answer": ["特に"] },
    { "question": "변하다", "answer": ["変わる"] },
    { "question": "불다", "answer": ["吹く"] },
    { "question": "빌리다", "answer": ["借りる"] },
    { "question": "쉬다", "answer": ["休む"] },
    { "question": "씻다", "answer": ["洗う"] },
    { "question": "얻다", "answer": ["もらう"] },
    { "question": "오르다", "answer": ["登る"] },
    { "question": "움직이다", "answer": ["動く"] },
    { "question": "생활하다", "answer": ["生活する"] },
    { "question": "세수하다", "answer": ["洗面する"] },
    { "question": "연습하다", "answer": ["練習する"] },
    { "question": "요구하다", "answer": ["要求する"] },
    { "question": "의미하다", "answer": ["意味する"] },
    { "question": "이해하다", "answer": ["理解する"] },
    { "question": "입학하다", "answer": ["入学する"] },
    { "question": "자라다", "answer": ["育つ"] },
    { "question": "정하다", "answer": ["定める"] },
    { "question": "죽다", "answer": ["死ぬ"] },
    { "question": "부르다", "answer": ["呼ぶ"] },
    { "question": "붙이다", "answer": ["付ける"] },
    { "question": "생기다", "answer": ["生じる"] },
    { "question": "싸우다", "answer": ["喧嘩する"] },
    { "question": "알리다", "answer": ["知らせる"] },
    { "question": "열리다", "answer": ["聞かれる"] },
    { "question": "외우다", "answer": ["覚える"] },
    { "question": "이기다", "answer": ["勝つ"] },
    { "question": "설명하다", "answer": ["説明する"] },
    { "question": "소개하다", "answer": ["紹介する"] },
    { "question": "예정하다", "answer": ["予定する"] },
    { "question": "유학하다", "answer": ["留学する"] },
    { "question": "이용하다", "answer": ["利用する"] },
    { "question": "인사하다", "answer": ["挨拶する"] },
    { "question": "잃어버리다", "answer": ["なくす"] },
    { "question": "전하다", "answer": ["伝える"] },
    { "question": "주무시다", "answer": ["お休みになる"] },
    { "question": "지내다", "answer": ["過ごす"] },
    { "question": "지다", "answer": ["負ける"] },
    { "question": "짓다", "answer": ["建てる / 炊く"] },
    { "question": "준비하다", "answer": ["準備する"] },
    { "question": "지각하다", "answer": ["遅刻する"] },
    { "question": "출발하다", "answer": ["出発する"] },
    { "question": "감동하다", "answer": ["感動する"] },
    { "question": "치다", "answer": ["打つ / 弾く / 叩く"] },
    { "question": "통하다", "answer": ["通じる"] },
    { "question": "풀다", "answer": ["ほどく・解く"] },
    { "question": "낳다", "answer": ["産む"] },
    { "question": "빠지다", "answer": ["落ちる・抜ける"] },
    { "question": "지키다", "answer": ["守る"] },
    { "question": "졸업하다", "answer": ["卒業する"] },
    { "question": "중요하다", "answer": ["重要とする"] },
    { "question": "지도하다", "answer": ["指導する"] },
    { "question": "필요하다", "answer": ["必要とする"] },
    { "question": "경험하다", "answer": ["経験する"] },
    { "question": "켜다", "answer": ["（スイッチ）つける"] },
    { "question": "틀리다", "answer": ["間違う"] },
    { "question": "피우다", "answer": ["吸う"] },
    { "question": "따르다", "answer": ["従う・懐く"] },
    { "question": "옮기다", "answer": ["移す"] }
  ]
}
